<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<nodes>
  <node>
    <Title>Sunday Bulletin Archive</Title>
    <Body>&lt;style type="text/css"&gt;
&lt;!--
.campaign {line-height: 125%; margin: 5px;}
//--&gt;
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;script language="javascript" src="//stjohnarmenianchurch.us1.list-manage.com/generate-js/?u=78d04d8302560ecef66676d78&amp;fid=47229&amp;show=20" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/bulletin-archive</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Artsakh Refugee Relief Fund</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt;On September 19, 2023, a devastating event shook the Armenian community to its core. Azerbaijan launched a brutal military assault on Artsakh, specifically targeting the ethnic Christian Armenian enclave in the city of Stepanakert and its surrounding villages. This was not just a military operation; it was a violent attack against innocent civilians. The aftermath has seen over 100,000 Artsakh Armenians being forcefully displaced due to Azerbaijan's intent on ethnic cleansing. Furthermore, structures that have stood for millennia, bearing testament to our rich history, are now under threat. The Azeris aim to obliterate these historic landmarks, erasing the evidence of Armenian Christians' indigenous presence on these lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of this immense tragedy, St. John and the Western Diocese is committed to making a significant impact. We aim to provide immediate and long-term assistance to those affected, ensuring that the displaced families receive the support they need during these trying times. Through the Artsakh Refugee Fund and the collective efforts of our community, we pledge to stand by our brothers and sisters from Artsakh, ensuring that their sacrifices and struggles are not in vain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How We Plan to Assist:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Immediate Relief:&lt;/strong&gt; Our efforts assocaited with the our Annual Food Festival will be aollocated toward church-support efforts. &lt;a href="https://stjohnarmenianchurch.com/articles/827/st-john-food-festival-and-our-artsakh-refugee-crisis-response"&gt;Read more about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long-term Assistance:&lt;/strong&gt; St. John's Artsakh Relief Fund pledges to work through the institutions of the Church to support efforts that will secure the long-term stabilty of families impacted by the crisis with oversight and transparency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How You Can Help:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donate:&lt;/strong&gt; Donate toward this cause using the form below&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get Involved:&lt;/strong&gt; Inquire through the church regarding ways you can be engaged by volunteering and organizing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spread the Word:&lt;/strong&gt; Spread the word online and in person about the plight of the Armenians from Artsakh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Message from Our Diocesan Primate, Abp. Hovnan Derderian&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WESTERN DIOCESE MISSIONS IN SUPPORT OF DISPLACED FAMILIES FROM ARTSAKH AND THE VISIT OF THE NEWLY-APPOINTED DELEGATION TO ARMENIA &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past few weeks, we witnessed the horrific forced displacement of our people from Artsakh, their ancestral homeland. We witnessed their despair, shared their struggles amidst the tragedy had befallen on our people with the loss of the sacred land of Artsakh. In our battle to exist in our ancestral land, we lost thousands of souls, churches, schools, homes, and cultural and historical monuments as well as 3,000 years of our history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amidst the calamity, more than a hundred thousand Armenians, leaving behind their life’s belongings, were forced to leave for Armenia within a matter of days. Regardless of age, they lacked life’s basic essentials of food, medicine, clothing, and housing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Artsakh Refugee Fund was established at the Western Diocese for this exact purpose. The ongoing mission will provide urgent humanitarian assistance to our brothers and sisters in dire need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adhering to the call, the Diocesan faithful have put their Christian faith into action to extend a lending hand to our brothers and sisters through your generosity. Incoming donations from the Diocesan faithful totaling more than $300,000 have been transferred to the Mother See of Holy Etchmiadzin in support of Artsakh's refugees in Armenia. Led by the Rev. Fr. Vazgen Boyajyan, the Rev. Fr. Mesrop Ash and Diocesan Council Chairman Mr. Vartan Nazerian, a special delegation has been established by the Western Diocese, the members of which will travel to Armenia at the end of November to assess the humanitarian crisis and oversee the distribution of the collected funds. While in Armenia, the Diocesan Primate will also meet with the delegation and will visit displaced families of Artsakh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We express our genuine gratitude to the faithful for their generous financial support and contribution to the Artsakh Refugee Fund and are eternally grateful to the Almighty God for blessing our Church and nation with such devout faithful, whose love for Church and nation is boundless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=72e2a249-205e-4dbc-8a8e-e95c1f04bb95"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our Commitment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/donate/refugee-relief</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Food Festival Wishlist</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;Dear St. John Supporter,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;We hope this letter finds you well. We are thrilled to announce the return of the St. John 78th Food Festival on Saturday, October 28, and Sunday, October 29, after a several-year hiatus due to Covid. This event is not just a celebration of our rich Armenian culture and community, but also our main fundraiser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;In previous years, your generous donations have helped us support vital local and Armenian charities, making a significant difference in our community. This year, we hope to do the same with your continued support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;As always the St. John parishioners are already working tirelessly to prepare your favorite Armenian dishes for this much-anticipated event. However, the success of this event relies heavily on your generous contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;We welcome your donations towards our Wish List items, or you can choose to donate in memory of your loved ones. If you are a business, we would be delighted to acknowledge your contribution, including your business name, address, and website. All donations are tax-deductible and donors will be gratefully recognized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;To contribute, please make your check out to St. John Armenian Church, or donate online at &lt;a href="https://stjohnarmenianchurch.com/food-festival/wishlist"&gt;stjohnarmenianchurch.com/food-festival/wishlist&lt;/a&gt;. No matter how small or large, we are deeply grateful for your kindness and generosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;With heartfelt thanks,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt;The Food Festival Committee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 dir="ltr"&gt;Our Wishlist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type="text/css"&gt;
&lt;!--/*--&gt;&lt;![CDATA[/* &gt;&lt;!--*/
#wishlist-table {
            width: 100%;
            border-collapse: collapse;
        }
        #wishlist-table thead tr {
            font-weight: bold;
            background-color: #f0f0f0;
        }
        #wishlist-table td {
            padding: 10px;
            border: 1px solid #ccc;
        }

/*--&gt;&lt;!]]&gt;*/
&lt;/style&gt;&lt;table id="wishlist-table"&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WHAT WE NEED&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HOW MANY&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;COST&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Legs of Lamb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100 legs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$50/per leg&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Eggs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 cases&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$25 per case&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wine&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15 cases&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$70/case&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Butter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;125 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$5/ lb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rice&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;225 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$5/ per 5 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Grape Leaves&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8 cases&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$100/case&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Compostable plates/bag&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6 cases&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$70/case&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Puff Pastry&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15 cases&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$25/case&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Flour&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;450 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$15 per 25lb&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Onions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$125 total&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Music Entertainment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$1,500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Outside&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$2,500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cheese&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;50 lbs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$1,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charcoal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Non alcoholic drinks&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ice&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Raffle&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$1,500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=a7ad05fb-d8a5-4e2a-9fb8-c5d068960a75"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/food-festival/wishlist</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Merry Christmas!</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="max-width:400px" class="media-element file-preview" data-delta="3" typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://dev-st-john.pantheonsite.io/sites/default/files/styles/media_thumbnail/public/Christ%20is%20born%20and%20revealed%21%20Blessed%20is%20the%20Revelation%20of%20Christ%21.png?itok=gIr0188s" width="1080" height="1080" alt="" title="" /&gt;Dear Faithful,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As we gather to celebrate the blessed feast of Armenian Christmas, it is with a heart full of joy and gratitude that I extend my warmest greetings to you all. This sacred occasion, commemorating the Nativity and Theophany of our Lord Jesus Christ, is a time to reflect on the profound mystery of God's love for us, manifested in the birth of His Son. It's a moment to rejoice in the light of Christ that shines upon us, guiding our path towards love, peace, and unity. Let us embrace this holy season as an opportunity to renew our faith and deepen our commitment to our spiritual journey and to the teachings of our beloved Armenian Apostolic Church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we observe Armenian Christmas on January 6, distinct from the December observances, it's crucial to pause and reflect on the significance of this timing. While the world around us may seem to have moved past the festive season, for us, it is a profound moment to contemplate and honor the incarnation of Christ. This period is not just a continuation of celebration but a sacred time to deeply appreciate the gift of Christ's ministry. It's a season that calls us to make space in our lives for prayer and gratitude, acknowledging the transformative power of Christ's presence in our world. Traditionally, this time is marked by the blessing of homes, a practice that fortifies our faith and brings our church into the heart of our families. I warmly encourage you to embrace this beautiful tradition. Please feel free to reach out to me if you are interested in organizing a home blessing in the coming weeks. Let us together invite the blessings of our Lord into our homes and hearts, renewing our faith and strengthening our community bonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to join us for our &lt;a href="https://stjohnarmenianchurch.com/calendar"&gt;ongoing celebration of the season&lt;/a&gt;, Christmas Day Divine Liturgy on Saturday at 10:30am, and this Sunday for Water Blessing and celebratory Christmas lunchon after Church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you have not done so already please consider contributing to our &lt;a href="https://stjohnarmenianchurch.com/donate/acyooutreach"&gt;ACYO's Annual Christmas Appeal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours in prayer,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Fr. Mesrop&lt;/p&gt;
</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/merry-christmas</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Support Families of Fallen Soldiers</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt;In response to the unprovocated attacks on soveriegn Armenian land in September of 2022, which claimed the lives of over 200 soldiers, the Western Diocese of the Armenian Church has made an unprecedented commitment. We have pledged to give $1500 as show of mutual support and pastoral compasssion to the families of each of the fallen soldiers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore our Diocese has taken on the responsibility of distributing these funds, home by home. A clergy representative of the Western Diocese has already begun the exhaustive process of visiting each household and personally delivering this support to ensure that it reaches each and every beneficiery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encourage our parish family to be a part of this important process by making a generous donation as an expression of our gratitude for the sacrifices these families have made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=03515c10-8f95-45d0-b6e4-db88b9aa2a40"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/donate/support-families-fallen-soldiers</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Fellowship Hour</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt;Fellowship Hours are one of the most important aspects of a fulfilling church experience. The Fellowship Hour is the time after Divine Liturgy each week when our parish serves coffee, tea, and snacks to the faithful. This is a wonderful time when attendees can relax together, catch up, and meet new people. It's also a great time for families to connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are asking our members to help support St. John by hosting a Fellowship Hour once a year. This is a simple task that will require the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bring some simple snacks to church on your Sunday (for example: fruit, cookies, or pastries)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About 30 min. before Divine Liturgy is over (around 11:45pm), begin preparing the snacks on the trays and plates available in the kitchen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Begin preparing hot water for tea, and coffee. (Instructions are provided and Parish Council members will be available to help)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay following the Divine Liturgy and make sure that the snacks and beverages are available for everyone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean and put away any items from the kitchen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This seems complicated, will anyone be able to help me and my family?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, we will be able to provide you with everything you need, and members of the Parish Council and others will always be around to support and answer any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What if I need to reschedule, or something comes up that Sunday?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is always possible that you will sign up to host a Fellowship Hour, but a conflict may arise. If this happens, just contact the Church Office and we will make arrangements. It may also happen that a memorial luncheon or event is scheduled the Sunday that you requested. Again, you will be contacted and arrangements will be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want to support the Fellowship Hour, but I don't have time to host. What can I do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We realize that our members are very busy. If you would like to support our Fellowship Hours, but aren't able to host one yourself, you can also make a small donation to the Fellowship Hour, and the Church will coordinate things on your behalf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can I sign up?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can sign up by filling out the form below, or by contacting the church office 415-661-1142.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=0b93fb97-a319-4a30-8e37-b39b3976982f"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/fellowship-hour</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Online Training &amp; Education</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt;Training and education are essential for members of the church, from childhood and through every phase of life. Each new challenge represents a moment in time when we can better understand our faith, and apply it in new and uplifting ways. It can be hard at times to me in person for essential classes and trainings, so we have developed several online courses for our members. This is an ongoing process and we welcome our your feedback regarding which courses you would appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When clicking on a course below, click "Enroll" to begin&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Religious Education&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="one-of-two block course"&gt;&lt;a href="https://app.servehq.church/stjohnsf/course/22737"&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/trainedup20/62f43538c67b2%20-%20117177897_4297141346994684_9082751595491172818_n.jpg" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://app.servehq.church/stjohnsf/course/22737"&gt;Understanding the Divine Liturgy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class="desc"&gt;In this course, each module will be portion from a seminar series entitled "Understanding the Divine Liturgy." Over five sections, each part of the Divine Liturgy will be introduced and the hymns, prayers, and liturgical actions associated with them will be explained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="two-of-two block course"&gt;&lt;a href="#"&gt;&lt;img class="media-element file-preview" data-delta="1" typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://dev-st-john.pantheonsite.io/sites/default/files/styles/media_thumbnail/public/1A22678F-4E47-4688-A8F5-8DB8221074AD.png?itok=aE6Btivv" width="1280" height="720" alt="" title="" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Whats the Difference? - Coming Soon&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class="desc"&gt;This is a course intended to inform faithful of the Armenian Apostolic Church about its unique standing in the broader Christian world, and to explicitly explain, in historical context, what differentiates the Armenian Church from other Christian Denominations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;
&lt;div class="one-of-two block course"&gt;&lt;a href="#"&gt;&lt;img class="media-element file-preview" data-delta="2" typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://dev-st-john.pantheonsite.io/sites/default/files/styles/media_thumbnail/public/7948153B-1631-4639-82DD-21A22DC9DBEE.png?itok=51K0ByOv" width="1280" height="720" alt="" title="" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Fresh Faith - Coming Soon&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class="desc"&gt;This course is intended as a refresher course on basic elements of the Christian faith, with an emphasis on simplicity, and focusing on essential beliefs and practices that enrich the church-based spiritual experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="two-of-two block course"&gt;&lt;a href="#"&gt;&lt;img class="media-element file-preview" data-delta="3" typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://dev-st-john.pantheonsite.io/sites/default/files/styles/media_thumbnail/public/46D4D12E-F3C7-4FCF-A145-C5233D53ED11.png?itok=MboviFtS" width="1280" height="720" alt="" title="" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Spiritual Practices - Coming Soon&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class="desc"&gt;This course is an overview of various spiritual practices that are practical counterparts of our faith, and support a healthy lifestyle. These include fasting, biblical study, and meditation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Acolyte Training&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="one-of-two course"&gt;&lt;a href="https://app.servehq.church/stjohnsf/course/13048"&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/trainedup20/stjohnsf%20-%20The-Key-to-True-Power.jpg" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://app.servehq.church/stjohnsf/course/13048"&gt;Becoming an Acolyte - Knowledge Component&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class="desc"&gt;Welcome to the Acolyte Training program. All the lessons in this section will focus on the knowledge necessary for a candidate to prepare for received the rank of Acolyte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="two-of-two block course"&gt;&lt;a href="https://app.servehq.church/stjohnsf/course/13700"&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/trainedup20/stjohnsf%20-%201458238484_Acolytes.jpg" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://app.servehq.church/stjohnsf/course/13700"&gt;Becoming an Acolyte - Skills Component &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class="desc"&gt;In this course, students will review necessary skills for the acolyte, particularly candle holding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Leadership Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="one-of-two block course"&gt;&lt;a href="https://app.servehq.church/stjohnsf/course/22744"&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/trainedup20/62f6d70c16871%20-%20Screen%20Shot%202022-08-12%20at%203.38.06%20PM.png" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href="https://app.servehq.church/stjohnsf/course/22744"&gt;Supporting Generative Vision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class="desc"&gt;In the Church, as well our professional life, it is essential to understand, appreciate, and focus on the values, mission, and vision that drive our choices and priorities. Whether you are reviewing exisiting directives, or strives to reorganize your organization or parish, this course is all about developing tools that drive cooporeration and vision-oriented actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</Body>
    <Main-Image>&lt;img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://dev-st-john.pantheonsite.io/sites/default/files/istockphoto-1124339065-612x612.jpg" width="612" height="408" alt="" /&gt;</Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/online-training-education</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Arev Children&#039;s Fund</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who in his great mercy gave us a new birth to a living hope through the resurrection of Jesus Christ from the dead.&lt;/em&gt; –1 Peter 1:3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lent is a season of reflection and sacrifice. Lent is also a time of life and promise. When you give a Lenten gift, it is an expression of hope and love for our Christian family. This year St. John Armenian Church is organizing a lenten fundraising effort to benefit the &lt;a href="http://downchildren.am"&gt;Arev Children's Center serving children with Down Syndrome in Armenia&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mission of Arev Children's Health and Education Center is to significantly improve the lives of children with Down syndrome in Armenia, provide medical care, education, and advocacy.  To accomplish this important mission, fundraising is a core part of their work – especially since Down syndrome is the least funded genetic condition in Armenia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can make a huge difference by donating to the Arev Children's Fund, your gift can transform the lives of others!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=b07076a3-ec80-42ff-8a73-a84aa0db69e3"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image>&lt;img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://dev-st-john.pantheonsite.io/sites/default/files/IMG_0619_0.jpeg" width="1276" height="659" alt="" /&gt;</Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/donate/arev</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Membership Dues</Title>
    <Body>&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=ea38be42-18c0-48e5-a43a-7b64395cd279"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/donate/dues</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Support the Armenians of Lebanon</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt;Join us as we respond to the call of our Diocesan Primate to collect humanitarian support for the Armenian community of Lebanon. Lebanon, in general, and the Lebanese Armenian community are in the midst of choatic circumstances, political and economic circumstances have left many families without access to the basic needs of life, such as fresh food, public services, and health care. The global Armenian Church is making effort to collectively organize by raising funds that will directly be used to distribute aid to these families. St. John Armenian Church will collect funds, to be distributed on behalf of our community for this cause. Donations can be made via the form below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information watch this video clip…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JdsQlCBbDzM?start=77" title="YouTube video player" width="560"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=0ed323bf-4b15-43dd-b8b8-ab9cc72141ad"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/donate/lebanon</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Sunday School Registration</Title>
    <Body>&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=e550ab41-9fec-4c95-a2ab-b86cbff81e0a"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/ss-registration</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Annual Picnic Voluneers</Title>
    <Body>&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=94dbaee0-cae1-4423-8725-6f4fde9aeb65"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/annual-picnic-voluneers</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Attending Services</Title>
    <Body>&lt;div class="row"&gt;
&lt;div class="welcome-panel"&gt;
&lt;div class="welcome-text"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Reopening News&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The church is open for public worship! As this process continues to rollout we encourage you to &lt;a href="https://stjohnarmenianchurch.com/coronavirus"&gt;check our COVID-19 response page&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're excited to have you join us to participate in our celebration of the Divine Liturgy. Perhaps you are new to San Francisco or have been worshiping online with us for some time, and this will be a new experience for you. We are truly looking forward to welcoming you to our parish. You are welcome to sign-up using the form below to give us a heads up that you'll be joining us. We also encourage you to visit our &lt;a href="https://stjohnarmenianchurch.com/new-our-church"&gt;new visitor's page &lt;/a&gt;or &lt;a href="https://stjohnarmenianchurch.com/walk-through-divine-liturgy"&gt;learn more about the Divine Liturgy&lt;/a&gt; before you attend. If you haven't participated in our Sunday services before you can also &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UClCJF2gmv7dqAaKc9svNqag"&gt;watch a recent service on our YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Church participants are welcome to register their attendance in advance, but this is no longer&amp;nbsp;required&lt;/strong&gt;. This is encouraged for first-time visitors, as we appreciate the opportunity to welcome them when they arrive and provide resources for them to have a fulfilling experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: please be sure to add all the members of your group when you reserve. Attendees can be added by clicking on &lt;em&gt;"&lt;/em&gt;Add Another Attendee".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=064b95ba-5966-4f2e-9c57-fee0a65c00e1&amp;custom-templates=null"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; --&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/reserve</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Easter 2021 Youghakin</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt;The tradition of offering oil continued in the Christian church with a different meaning. Believers would bring oil or donate money towards the purchase of oil in order to keep the oil-burning lanterns lit. From our Christian perspective, burning lanterns symbolize our living faith in Jesus Christ, who is the light himself. Our Lord Jesus Christ says, “I am the light of the world; he who follows me will not walk in darkness but will have the light of life” (John 8:12).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you send your Youghakin donations, you are refueling the symbolic lantern of faith, which St. Gregory the Illuminator lighted many years ago. At this Christmastide, once again we invite you to ignite the kindling love of God in your hearts from the traditional lantern of St. Gregory as we all try to renew our faith and spiritual life. With this letter, we will enclose a special self-addressed envelope, which you can use for sending your generous Youghakin donations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also support our parish and make your Youghakin contribution online. Just visit stjohnarmenianchurch.com, and click “Donate". We thank you in advance for your consideration and kindness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=a1d5afe6-80a0-4195-ae7e-a4c5b5f0d658&amp;custom-templates="&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/donate/easter-2021-youghakin</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>The Stateless Diplomat</Title>
    <Body>&lt;div style="padding:56.25% 0 0 0;position:relative;"&gt;&lt;iframe allow="autoplay; fullscreen" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/432917771" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src="https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/432886849"&gt;THE STATELESS DIPLOMAT&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/mimimalayan"&gt;Mimi Malayan&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p style="color: #fff"&gt; Join us for the Q&amp;A with Mimi Malayan on Saturday, December 19 at 7:00pm. &lt;a href="https://us02web.zoom.us/meeting/register/tZwrdu-orjotHdIRzRNFfB5h-Djl96_lMFw_"&gt;Click here to register for the Zoom event&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style type="text/css"&gt;
body { background-color: #111; }
.page__title { color: #fff }
&lt;/style&gt;

</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/stateless/viewing</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Chaplaincy Support Fund</Title>
    <Body>&lt;!--
&lt;h3&gt;Announcing "Christmas Gifts For Armenian Soldiers"&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear members of the Armenian community in San Francisco, USA, we each have different circumstances of our lives that enable us to live happily, safely, and lovingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the eve of these Christmas holidays, the Armenian soldier and commander, who voluntarily deprived themselves of that sense of security, stood at the border, risking their own lives, and allowed us to be happy and safe. And it does not matter if we live in Armenia, the United States or anywhere in the world. We each owe it to the Armenian Soldier and Commander for their high sense of self-sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, St. John's Church is organizing the "CHRISTMAS GIFT TO THE ARMENIAN SOLDIER" initiative, which will allow us to prepare Christmas presents and send them to the Armenian Soldier and Commander guarding the Armenian Borders. Therefore, we look forward to your active participation on this occasion with your modest financial support to make the project a success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE&lt;/b&gt; In addition to the support we are sending to our soldiers, we are also asking for donations to help our chaplains as well. We have been informed that many of those who are serving in Artsakh are in need of material support, so we are also working through our chaplaincy fund to help them during the difficult circumstances caused by the blockade.&lt;/p&gt;--&gt;
&lt;!--
&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning of the current war in defense of Artsakh, young Armenian men and women have valiantly fought and given their lives for the defense of Artsakh, and from the first day, the chaplains of the Armenian Church have been by their side, supporting them in any way possible by sacrament, prayer, and encouragement. The chaplains have also taken on the role of helping to rapidly obtain essential items for their entrusted flock, such as warm underclothing and wet weather gear. Simple items like these can mean the difference between life and death. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; We have been passionate supporters of the chaplaincy program for years, which has been impeccably accountable and effective in their collaboration with us. We have established a fund to help them in their God-pleasing mission, and in a matter of days, by our humble support, soldiers have already begun to receive these basic but crucial items. Your contribution to this fund will help them in their God-pleasing service.&lt;/p&gt;
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Chaplaincy Support Fund is a critical initiative that funds the work of our devoted Army Chaplains in Armenia. These dedicated chaplains are on the front lines, providing pastoral care, teaching, advocacy, and spiritual guidance to our brave soldiers, strengthening their moral foundation, and providing hope in the challenging environment of military life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our chaplains are not just spiritual guides; they are mentors, advocates, and a source of strength for our soldiers. They teach essential Christian principles that help our soldiers navigate the psychological and spiritual impacts of military life. From the base to the front lines, their presence is a source of comfort and reassurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chaplaincy Support Fund also enables our chaplains to organize religious pilgrimages throughout our homeland. These journeys inspire our soldiers and connect them more deeply with their faith and their Armenian heritage. In addition, our chaplains regularly organize sacramental services, including Divine Liturgy at military chapels and baptisms, further enriching the spiritual lives of our soldiers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we cannot sustain this essential work without your help. Your donation to the Chaplaincy Support Fund will directly support these invaluable services, ensuring that our soldiers have access to pastoral care, spiritual guidance, and the enriching experiences that strengthen their resolve and fortify their spirits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please consider making a generous contribution to the Chaplaincy Support Fund today. Your donation will make a profound difference in the lives of our soldiers, providing them with the spiritual sustenance they need in their service to our nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=d47834e2-00e1-4998-9c87-758bef1ed37b&amp;custom-templates="&gt;&lt;/script&gt;--&gt;
&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=5fd83a70-141c-4dda-be17-cde9326a1fd8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p style="color: #ccc; font-style: italic;" &gt;Please wait for donation form to load&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image>&lt;img typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://dev-st-john.pantheonsite.io/sites/default/files/C714AABC-93D3-4926-AC01-E53686C06261.jpeg" width="1028" height="823" alt="" /&gt;</Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/donate/chaplains</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Artsakh Support Fund</Title>
    <Body>&lt;!--&lt;div class="row"&gt;
&lt;div class="one-of-two"&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/adxPme9eCw4?start=99" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="two-of-two"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The most effective way for us to support Armenia and Artsakh is to donate funds for humanitarian aid via ArmeniaFund. By concentrating all our resources, we can ensure that the necessary response can be made on the ground in Armenia. Furthermore, we are so committed to encouraging our community to donate quickly and generously that St. Johns is going to be matching any donation we receive between now and October 7th up to a total of $15,000. Donate via our website today to double your contribution to the effort while this program lasts. They’re counting on us.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; --&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align:center; margin: 0 auto;"&gt;&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/adxPme9eCw4?start=99" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;
&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=94697e1b-598b-4ff5-a8d7-95e4c5c7c82a&amp;custom-templates="&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/donate/artsakh</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Our Church App</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Church App" style="float:right;" class="media-element file-default media-float-right" data-delta="1" typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://dev-st-john.pantheonsite.io/sites/default/files/styles/medium/public/m1_support_material_social_wood_2.png?itok=3ct-W2HI" width="220" height="220" title="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try our new church app. It’s a great way to stay connected with St. John.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access live streams and our latest videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Register for upcoming events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit prayer requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give towards church programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access member directory (for dues paying members only)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download Church App from the buttons below and after its installed search for "St. John Armenian Church"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="48" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" src="https://fellowshipone.ministryone.com/api/v2/organizations/organization/embed/contents?churchId=62641" width="275"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/app</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>St. John Armenian Church Podcast</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt;Featuring spiritual messages, special announcements, and in-depth podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe frameborder="no" height="300" scrolling="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/users/278937664&amp;color=ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false" width="100%"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/st-john-armenian-church-podcast</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Podcasts</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt;Listen to our podcasts. Available, and where you listen to podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/stjohnpodcast"&gt;St. John Armenian Church Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/janabar"&gt;Janabar Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/podcasts</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Janabar Podcast</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt;Our daily podcast featuring brief reflections, quotes, and inspirational messages to encourage the faithful on their spiritual path or “janabar.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a class="spreaker-player" href="https://www.spreaker.com/show/janabar-daily" data-resource="show_id=4564991" data-width="100%" data-height="350px" data-theme="light" data-playlist="show" data-playlist-continuous="false" data-autoplay="false" data-live-autoplay="false" data-chapters-image="true" data-episode-image-position="right" data-hide-logo="false" data-hide-likes="false" data-hide-comments="false" data-hide-sharing="false" data-hide-download="true"&gt;Listen to "Janabar Daily" on Spreaker.&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/janabar-daily/id1530445658"&gt;&lt;img src="https://mk0podcastinsigfjx7m.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/apple-podcasts-badge-300.png" alt="Apple Podcasts" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="spotify:show:32khvnJFB7MuNT2sQrBAzX"&gt;&lt;img src="https://mk0podcastinsigfjx7m.kinstacdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/spotify-podcast-badge-blk-grn-330x80-300x73.png" alt="Spotify Podcasts" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;script async src="https://widget.spreaker.com/widgets.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;style type="text/css"&gt;
#page-title {
background: url(https://stjohnarmenianchurch.com/sites/default/files/styles/media_thumbnail/public/Copy%20of%20Copy%20of%20JANABAR.jpg?itok=wTqn19Z0);
color: #fff;
padding: .25em .5em;
text-shadow: 1px 1px 5px rgba(0,0,0,.5);
line-height: 1.5em;
}
&lt;/style&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/janabar</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Online Check-In</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt;Thanks for joining our streaming worship service! By filling the form below you can let us know that you were praying with us. If you've never participated before, you'll be added to our mailing list. If you're a regular attendee we'll be reasssured to know that you are joinung us once again. Depending on the service, you may be elegible to win a raffle if you check-in. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=910a5d79-9e1a-4197-b82f-617be6222784&amp;custom-templates="&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/check-in</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Unified College Scholarship Application</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2023 College Scholarship Applications are due by November 30, 2023&lt;/b&gt;. For any questions please email &lt;a href="mailto:info@stjohnarmenianchurch.com"&gt;info@stjohnarmenianchurch.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;AWARD PROGRAMS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The James Martin Klijian Memorial Fund Scholarship Awards of St. John Armenian Apostolic Church was established by The Barkev and Beatrice Klijian Family in 1976 in memory of James Martin Klijian. Scholarships are available each year for the purpose of encouraging participation in St. John Armenian Church youth activities. One requirement of this fund is applicants or one parent must be a pledging member of St. John Armenian Apostolic Church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, auxiliary organizations and private donors award scholarships to the youth of our parish who have demonstrated their devotion to the Armenian Church over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;ELIGIBILITY&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Award Selection Committee will determine which applicant should receive the award in accordance with the following standards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applicants must be young men or women between the ages of 17-24 who are active in St. John Church youth activities, such as the Sunday School, ACYO, Church Choir, Acolytes, and other programs;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This Scholarship cannot be awarded to an individual more than four (4) times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As many as two (2) letters of recommendation may be submitted for consideration, but are not required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=537ccce0-62ab-4659-ad13-a98611d62cd2"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/unified-college-scholarship-application</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>Find a Group</Title>
    <Body>&lt;p&gt;There are so many program that you can join to express your devotion and apply your God-given gifts. Please take a look at the list below and click Join if you are interested in finding out more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style="width:98%;border:0;min-height:800px" id="groupFinderFrame" src="https://stjohnchurch.fellowshiponego.com/groupfinder?defaultView=list"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script src="https://stjohnchurch.fellowshiponego.com/media/js/groupFinderiFrame.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/find-group-0</Path>
  </node>
  <node>
    <Title>New Member Application</Title>
    <Body>&lt;script src="https://forms.ministryforms.net/embed.aspx?formId=18b7b492-b047-4794-a490-b9bdf3aa21ac&amp;custom-templates="&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</Body>
    <Main-Image></Main-Image>
    <More-Images></More-Images>
    <Path>/new-member</Path>
  </node>
</nodes>
